# MARTIN DAPROTIS

# Computer Systems Engineer

646 Sgo. Del Estero., Bahía Blanca, Bs As, CP 8000

+54 9 2994568950

mdaprotis@hotmail.com

in Linkedin.com/in/martin-daprotis/

# **Summary of qualifications**

I am a Computer Systems Engineer graduated from Universidad Nacional del Sur in 2014. Familiarized with a variety of programming languages for web development and embedded systems. I am currently working as a Ssr Front End Developer, nevertheless I have worked as a Sr Full-Stack Developer for more than 6 years on both Back-End and Front-End, gathering requirements, designing UI, developing, testing and debugging our systems.

## **Technical Skills**

#### **FRONT END**

| <ul> <li>JavaScript</li> </ul> | <ul> <li>AJAX</li> </ul>  | <ul> <li>React Testing Library</li> </ul> |
|--------------------------------|---------------------------|---|
| <ul> <li>ReactJs</li> </ul>    | <ul> <li>Redux</li> </ul> | <ul> <li>Redux Thunk</li> </ul>           |
| • ES6+                         | <ul> <li>REST</li> </ul>  | <ul> <li>GraphQL</li> </ul>               |
| <ul> <li>JQuery</li> </ul>     | <ul> <li>JEST</li> </ul>  | <ul> <li>Apollo Client</li> </ul>         |

## UI/UX

CSS3

**Styled Components** 

- SASS
- BootStrap
- Material UI

| TD | A . | TA # | TT  | AT    | $\sim$ T | N II 7 | ~ |
|----|-----|------|-----|-------|----------|--------|---|
| FR | Δ   | IVI  | H / | /N/ I |          | гк.    | • |
|    |     |      |     |       |          |        |   |

- CodeIgniter
- Next<sub>J</sub>s

#### **BACK-END**

- PHP
- Python
- **Node**Is
- **Express**

## **DATABASE**

- MySQL
- MongoDB/Mongoos
- Oracle
- Informix

| CVS | AGILE | OTHERS  |
|-----|-------|---------|
| CVS | AUILL | OTTLINS |

- Git **SCRUM** Docker **Docker Compose** GitHub JIRA

  - **GitFlow** Redmine

## **Personal Skills**

#### COMMUNICATION

During my work experience as a Full Stack Web Developer I had to meet with the client in order to gather requirements to start the development process of new Systems. Additionally, was responsible for answering client enquiries by phone solving their problems and giving support on systems which I was maintaining.

#### RESPONSABILITY

I was responsible for developing and maintaining systems with sensible data such as employee salaries or bank transactions systems. Those systems were crucial to make the monthly payments of the 4000+ employees of the company.

#### **TEAMWORK**

Even though I had to work in some cases on my own it is always better to face challenges as a team. For more than 5 year now, I have been part of a development team, in which all members participate in a collaborative way with SCRUM methodologies.

#### **ADAPTABILITY**

This skill is mandatory to work in web development, often when I encounter new challenges it is necessary to investigate and get some insight about new technologies, packages or libraries.

# **Work Experience**

## SSR FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER | BGLOBAL SOLUTIONS | SEP 2020 - PRESENT

Working on an integration of a **headless Magento 2**, and a **WordPress** webpage into a **NextJs** based website using **React Storefront** with a custom connector in order to consume the **GraphQL Magento 2 API**. We are also implementing inside this page an institutional page in the same site.

### SR FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER COOPERATIVA OBRERA | JAN 2015 - SEP 2020

Developed a vast variety of systems, taking responsibility of the full process of internal websites contained in an Intranet portal used by the entire company. We worked with Continuous Integration and Deployment on internal servers, all the development is carried out in a **Dockerized** environment applying **SCRUM** methodology.

For more than 5 years I have been working with a **LAMP** stack using **CodeIgniter** (MVC) as a main framework:

- Back End: Initially using PHP 5.6 and then making a transition to PHP 7.0 in all of our systems.
- **Front End:** (Single Page Websites) using **Javascript**, **JQuery**, **AJAX**, **JSON**, **ES6+** always optimizing the Front-End with lazy loading and reducing the amount of http requests on demand.

- **UI**: own styled elements using **CSS** and **SASS** avoiding the dependencies of third party's libraries.
- **DB**: design and optimize **MySQL** queries with transactional operations, generating triggers and stored procedures in necessary cases.

Three years ago, we moved on to a **MERN (MySQL, ExpressJs, ReactJs, NodeJs)** stack applying **TDD** to the process with **JEST** and **RTL**.

## SCRIPT WRITER | ALAS INGENIERIA | JUL 2014 - JAN 2015

In this 6-month project, I was in charge of the migration of the Smart Plant Foundation database for PROFERTIL . The database was an Oracle DB and the migration was carried out with scripts to migrate and control the assertion of the process, fulfilling the necessary requirements to meet ISO-9001 standards

#### **FREELANCE**

- Ecommerce web page for local business: Develop an e-commerce website allowing local businesses to overcome COVID-19 difficulties to sell as they normally did, the technologies used were MERN stack (MongoDB, Express, React, Redux, NodeJs) with Material UI, and Stripe/MercadoPago payment gateways.
- Customized Professional Portfolios: This Front-End project was developed with React and Material UI for professionals like Layers, Fitness Teachers, etc.
- *Crawler Scripts:* Developed scripts with PHP and Python allowing the client to track FedEx and UPS packages, synchronizing information with Google Sheets.

# **Qualifications**

UNIVERSIDAD NACIONAL DEL SUR

COMPUTER SYSTEMS ENGINEERING

# Languages

**ENGLISH:** *UPPER INTERMEDIATE* 

**SPANISH**: *NATIVE*